Thank you,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Mr. Chairman. Thank you for being here today to answer our questions. Since 2014, the Department of Homeland Security, and in particular the Office of Inspector General at the Department of Homeland Security, has been covertly auditing and inspecting security-related aspects of TSA. And it's done so, as far as I'm aware, about four times.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): The IG's findings have revealed some very alarming rates of failure, of failure due to both human and technology-based failures. Most recently, in February of this year, the IG conducted covert testing on procedures to safeguard the so-called secure
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): areas of airports, finding both human-based and technology-based vulnerabilities at various points. And the IG made a series of six recommendations in response to the perception of those failures. As of two months ago, each of the six recommendations made by the IG were still open.
What
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): can you tell us about the current status of the IG's recommendations, and when can we
Speaker 2: expect that those will be closed?
We have
Speaker 3: concurred with all of the recommendations, individual recommendations, and are actively working to address them. A number of these recommendations are ones highlighting some areas that we also believe
Speaker 3: into the larger discussion we are having around insider threat and the need to do more in insider threat. Not only are we looking to rapidly respond to those requirements, we are also looking at what this tells us and how it informs our wider recognition. We would be happy to provide you
Speaker 4: some additional discussion in perhaps a different setting as to some of the details of the requirement.
Speaker 5: Thank you. Overall, we have seen this several times in the last few years. What do you feel about the overall trajectory of how
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): it's going? Overall,
we
Speaker 3: believe that it's critically important that not only the Inspector General, but we ourselves do continual covert testing on our own programs and own processes. We look at not only how are we performing against the standards we set ourselves originally, how we were set up
Speaker 7: to meet threats, are we meeting the threats we were set up for, but also as the threats changed,
Speaker 7: How are we positioned against those new threats, the ones we weren't designed originally to meet?
Thank
Speaker 8: you. I'd encourage
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): you to do that. As you can imagine, there is a significant deprivation of a person's privacy and liberty when a person is stopped
Speaker 9: along the way, and most of the time, the way these things work, the overwhelming majority of the
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): people you're stopping, inconveniencing, and people whose privacy is being violated are the innocent people. So
.
And in order
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): to do that, we need to make sure that whatever we're doing is working and is done in the most minimally invasive means possible. TSA has recently been collaborating with U.S.
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): Customs and Border Protection over the testing of facial recognition technology. Can you tell me a little bit about what the TSA's timeline is for the widespread adoption of facial recognition technology and...
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): I'd also like to know what the TSA does when it collects this information. Does it collect it
for any
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): purpose other than as a verification for the person's
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): ID? Does it now or will it in the future be keeping that data?
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): for any longer than is necessary to perform the task at hand, or how long do they keep it?
So we are
Speaker 11: conducting two types of pilots. The first one, as you noted, is with Customs and Border Protection.
The
Speaker 3: way that process works is based on how many people who we think is going to be flying any individual day, based on who the carriers tell us have bought tickets.
Speaker 3: CBP helps pre-position a gallery of photos of individuals whose passports are already on file, passport photos. As they approach a checkpoint, we are able to do a match against that smaller number of parties. So we are not widely screening against large sets of data. We are looking for you to match
you. The
Speaker 3: second type of pilot we are doing just started recently out at McCarran Airport in Las Vegas. That one, using our credential authentication technology, looks at matching you
to your
the
Speaker 3: facial image on your driver's license or other document under both circumstances we retain long enough to do the
match for
Speaker 3: initial auditing and then we are not storing and in that
Speaker 12: sense what happens in Vegas stays in Vegas yes
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): until 2016 new TSOs often completed their
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): training requirements at or near their home airports. It's my understanding that TSOs now receive training at a centralized TSA academy located at the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center in Georgia. Since this has happened, has TSA had any budget savings as a result of
that?
So, as you
Speaker 13: correctly know, we changed our process and we've changed it slightly again
Speaker 3: in this past year. What we have done is as a new TSO comes on board, they first are at their home airport for a period of time, about six months, and then they go off to the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center in Glencoe. This lets us go through an initial process and procedure to bring them on
board.
Speaker 3: continue to ensure that they are a good fit for the position that we are tracking them for prior to undergoing the two-week training down in Glencoe. What we have seen coming out of the training in Glencoe is not as much a budgetary savings per se as a consistency of training and camaraderie of spirit as people meet and retain those relationships across multiple airports. It enables them to know what another airport is doing against the same problem as well as what their home airport does. I
see my time's
Speaker 14: expired. Thank you very much.